Guide to the George W. Williams Papers, 1950-2005.
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
George W. Williams papers 1950-2005
University Archives, Duke University
Williams, George Walton, 1922-.
4.1 Linear Feet 5,000 Items
George Williams taught in the English Department at Duke University.
His collection includes lecture materials, correspondence, department and University correspondence, memoranda, and conference memorabilia.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The George W. Williams Papers, 1950-2005 were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1982, 1990-2002, and 2007.
Biographical Note
George Walton Williams was born in 1922 in Charleston, SC. He fought in France and Germany during World War II. He received his A.B. from Yale in 1947 and his M.A. and Ph.D. from the University of Virginia in 1949 and 1957, respectively. In the meantime, he also studied the history of his parish church and published a volume on the subject in 1951, entitled St. Michael's, Charleston, 1751-1951. Williams began teaching in the English Department at Duke in 1957, with specialties in Shakespeare and Richard Crashaw. In 1966, he was voted "Outstanding Professor" by the Duke student body. He is currently (2006) Professor Emeritus in Duke's English Department.
Collection Overview
Contains personal correspondence, Graduate School and English Department memoranda, campus committee minutes and correspondence, conference programs and organizational materials, materials relating to Duke's program in Continuing Education for College Faculty.
Removed rubber bands for preservation, discarded 7 folders of student grades and employment records.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Dept. of English -- Faculty.
Duke University -- Faculty.
Williams, George Walton, 1922-.
Related Material
Department of English Records, 1926-ongoing.
University Archives. Duke University.
Frank C. Brown Papers, 1899-1943.
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 7 Boxes
  - Marshall Scholarship Committee (Box 1)
  - Drama Committee
  - Friends of the Library
  - Correspondence with Terry Sanford Re: Shakespeare Controversy, 1982
  - East Campus
  - English 123/143, 1957-1993
  - English 124/144, 1957-1993
  - Provost's Committee on Art Department Review
  - East Art Museum, Long Range Planning
  - Faculty Episcopalians
  - Printing Exhibition
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1989
  - University Business Correspondence and Memoranda
  - MLA Shakespeare Division Papers
  - Shakespeare Association of America Papers
  - Nixon Library Correspondence, 1981
  - Addition: Papers, 1962-1972, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Summer Institute Application Form and Miscellaneous Information, 1965
  - College Entrance Examination Board: Committee on English Summer Institutes, 1962-1965
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966
  - Summer Institute, 1966
  - Summer Institute Correspondence, 1965
  - Summer Institute, 1972
  - Final Report, 1966-1967
  - National Defense Education Act Institute (NDEA) Budget
  - NDEA - Measurement Research Center, 1966-1967
  - NDEA - Miscellaneous Advertising
  - National Summer Institute, 1967, 1968
  - NDEA - Washington, 1965, 1966
  - NDEA - Workshops
  - South Atlantic Modern Language Association (Box 3)
  - Nominations, 1970-1973
  - Executive Committee Memoranda and Correspondence, 1970-1973
  - General Correspondence, 1968
  - General Correspondence, 1979
  - Louisville Conference, 1981
  - 1981 Course
  - General Correspondence, 1982
  - Nominations, 1983
  - Duke Folger Institute, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1970-1973
  - East Campus Committee, 1980-1981
  - East Campus Committee, 1979-1980
  - East for Frosh: Student Essays
  - Minutes, Memoranda, Etc. Concerning Hiring, 1985 - RESTRICTED
  - Commencement Committee - RESTRICTED
  - Intergovernmental Council Curriculum Committee, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Academic Council Correspondence, 1978-1981
  - University Faculty Council, Executive Committee - Personnel, 1981-1982
  - Building and Grounds Committee, Board of Trustees, 1980-1982
  - University Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences, Executive Committee, 1981-1982
  - University Faculty Council, Executive Committee Business, 1981-1982
  - Minutes of University Faculty Council Committees, 1980-1982
  - Miscellaneous Papers, undated (Box 6)
  - Humanities Faculty Seminar, 1976
  - Lilly Seminar, 1976
  - Lilly Reformers, 1976-1977
  - [Salem Academy Visit, 1962-1963]
  - [Academic Council, 1967-1975]
  - [Southeastern Renaissance Conference, 1961]
  - [Southeastern Renaissance Conference - Contributors' Correspondence, 1958-1960]
  - [Correspondence Re: Press Variants, 1970-1972]
  - S.A.M.L.A. Convention, 1980
  - S.A.M.L.A. /S.A.R. Editorial Board, 1982-1985
  - Committee on Sophomore English, 1965-1973 (Box 7)
  - Freshman English Committee, 1969-70
  - Miscellaneous Duke Correspondence, 1994-
  - Duke Correspondence re: Politics and University stuff, 1960-2001
  - Duke Correspondence re: Grounds, 1960-2005